To honour a promise. To find his sons. To make his peace.
The Water Diviner is a war, drama film directed by Russell Crowe.
In 1919, Australian farmer Joshua Connor travels to Turkey to discover
the fate of his three sons, reported missing in action.
Holding on to hope, Joshua must travel across the war-torn
landscape to find the truth and his own peace.
Joshua Connor, played by Russell Crowe.
Ayshe, played by Olga Kurylenko.
Major Hasan, played by Yılmaz Erdoğan.
Sgt. Jemal, played by Cem Yılmaz.
Lt. Colonel Hughes, played by Jai Courtney.
Arthur "Art" Connor, played by Ryan Corr.
The Water Diviner is a 2014 drama film starring and directed by Russell Crowe, in his
directorial debut, and written by Andrew Anastasios and Andrew Knight.
The film follows an Australian farmer, Joshua Connor (Crowe), who travels to Turkey
soon after World War I to find his three sons who never returned.
It also stars Olga Kurylenko, Jai Courtney, Cem Yılmaz,
Yılmaz Erdoğan, and Jacqueline McKenzie.
The Water Diviner had its world premiere at the State
Theatre in Sydney, Australia on 2 December 2014.
It opened in Australian and New Zealand cinemas on Boxing Day 2014.
The film had a limited release in the United States on 24 April 2015.
At the 4th AACTA Awards, it won for Best Film and Erdoğan won
the AACTA Award for Best Supporting Actor.
The film explores themes of australia, based on true story,
post world war i, farmer, missing in action.
The tone is emotional.